Navid Mashinchi

nmashinchi@gmail.com | 916-330-0268 | Irvine, CA | Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

SUMMARY:

Data professional with 4+ years of experience within the field of analytics. Currently working as a Data Scientist I at Kohl's, Adjunct Professor at the University of Denver and a Data Science Mentor at SharpestMinds. KDnuggets Silver Blog and Streamlit New User of the Month award winner.

EDUCATION & AWARDS

Master's in Data Science, University of Denver, Denver, CO, USA

August 2021

- GPA: 3.92/4.00
- Relevant Courses: DS Mathematics 1 & 2, DS Statistics 1 & 2, Database Organization & Management, Algorithms, DS Tools 1 & 2, Machine Learning, Data Mining, Data Visualization, Parallel and Distributed Computing for Data Science.

Full Stack Web Development Certification, Thinkful, New York, NY, USA

August 2019

• Modules included: Front-End & Back-End Fundamentals, Front-End Frameworks, Computer Science Fundamentals & Server-Side JS.

Bachelor of Commerce, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada

December 2015

• Specialization: Accounting

KDnuggets Silver Blog – March Award, Award Link

April 2021

• Earned the KDnuggets Silver Blog March award for having over 9000 views for my article: "The Portfolio Guide for Data Science Beginners".

Streamlit New User of the Month Award, Award Link

March 2021

• Earned the new user of the month award for my COVID-19 dashboard (web app) and articles that I shared.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, R, JavaScript.
- Data Science: Data Cleaning & Wrangling (Pandas, NumPy), Data Visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Folium, Geoplot, Ggplot2), Big Data (Spark), Statistics, Hypothesis Testing, Modeling, Interpretation.
- Machine Learning: Scikit-Learn, Supervised ML, Unsupervised ML, TensorFlow, Keras.
- Databases & Others: SQL, MongoDB, Relational Algebra, ER Modeling, GitHub, Git, Streamlit, Heroku, HTML, CSS, Node.JS.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist I, Kohl's, Remote

June 2022 - Present

Adjunct Professor, University of Denver, Remote

June 2022 – Present

- Lecture graduate students enrolled in Database Organization and Management I.
- Provide office hours for graduate students to answer questions regarding course materials.
- Answer emails from students to ensure proper understanding of the course materials.
- Evaluate student work and record grades.

Data Science Mentor, SharpestMinds, Remote, Mentor Profile

May 2022 - Present

- Provide guidance to aspiring data scientists on how to break into the industry.
- Support mentees with networking support, one-on-one calls, mock interviews, and code review.

Associate Data Scientist, Kohl's, Remote

September 2021 – May 2022

• Building machine learning models in Python for the Supply Chain team to predict when inventory will arrive at particular supply chain journey segments to provide the logistics team with better information for planning purposes.

- Participating in the data science internship committee to assess prospective interns for the data science department by conducting behavioral and technical interviews.
- Publishing data science blogs for Kohl's Data Science Medium group to showcase projects and share experiences gained as a data scientist at Kohl's.

Data Science Internship, Opeeka, Sacramento, CA, USA

June 2021 - August 2021

- Developed a data quality dashboard by cleaning, combining, formatting, and filtering customer data utilizing SQL and Sisense for Opeeka's Person-Centered Intelligence Solution (P-CIS).
- Visualized well-being survey results using R for senior leadership to better understand well-being satisfaction levels across different domains.
- Researched statistical methods for the senior data scientist on the appropriateness of the technique for future projects.

Graduate Teaching Assistant, University of Denver, Remote

June 2021 – August 2021

- Assisted graduate students enrolled in Data Science Tools 1 and Data Science Tools 2 with course materials during office hours.
- Answered emails from students to ensure proper understanding of the course materials.
- Evaluated student work for both courses and recorded grades.

Lead Analyst, Vancouver Whitecaps FC, Vancouver, BC, Canada

June 2016 – February 2018

- Managed the analytics department, consisting of one full-time analyst and three interns after losing the supervisor without a drop-in output by providing consistent analytical services to the staff, players, and senior leadership resulting in reaching the MLS playoffs.
- Created 34+ analytical reports on the opposition through data collection and uncovering patterns and trends for the MLS coaching staff.
- Presented research findings to coaches weekly and wrote requested summaries detailing the department's state to senior leadership.

Assistant Analyst, Vancouver Whitecaps FC, Vancouver, BC, Canada

January 2015 - May 2016

- Led a team of three interns, trained them on the department's operations procedures, resulting in one full-time hire.
- Supported the department head by analyzing future opposition through statistical and video analysis.
- Collected and analyzed data on prospective incoming players to help the club make better decisions on player acquisitions.

Performance Analyst Internship, Vancouver Whitecaps FC, Vancouver, BC, Canada

June 2014 – December 2014

- Launched a live stats application by developing an MS Excel spreadsheet that streamed real-time data to the coaches electronic devices.
- Oversaw the club's video database by managing, filming, sharing training and game footages to 100+ employees.

PROJECTS

An Examination of Fatal Force by Police in the United States | GitHub

October 2020 – November 2020

- Examined the factors that play into the horrible event of a fatal shooting by the US police.
- Predicted mental illness status by implementing a Logistic Regression, SVC, SGD, Decision Tree, and Random Forest.
- Improved the accuracy score from 72% to 77% by fine-tuning the final model using RandomizedSearchCV.

Predicting number of COVID-19 deaths using Time Series Analysis | GitHub

August 2020 – September 2020

- Predicted the number of deaths in the US starting from August 1 August 21 and August 1 November 1.
- Implemented the differencing technique to make the data stationary to conduct a time series analysis using the ARIMA model.
- Forecasted 18589 deaths and CNN projected 19000 deaths between August 1 and August 21.
- Forecasted 235967 deaths and CNN projected 231000 deaths between August 1 and November 1. The actual death number, according to Worldometer, was 236072.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Student Ambassador Data Science Master's Program, Remote

November 2020 - August 2021

• Spoke to prospective students and participated in student panel webinars, round tables, and in PR opportunities.